<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<search>
  
  <entry>
    <title>CDA3103 - Computer Logic and Organization </title>
    <url>/course/test/</url>
    <categories><category></category>
    </categories>
    <tags>
    </tags>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[CDA3103 - Computer Logic and Organization Summer 2014 Class description: Functional overview of computer systems, interconnection of basic components, system performance measures, instruction set design, arithmetic logic unit, control unit, memory system, pipelining, interrupts and input-output. Instructor: Mr. Saad Ahmad Khan Teaching Assistants: Mr Junyao Zhang (zhangjunyao5518@gmail.com)
Office Hours: Wed 4:00pm - 5:00pm (in HEC-231)
Office: HEC - 315 Phone: (on last resort) E-mail: skhan@eecs.ucf.edu (preferred means of communication) Web Site: http://www.eecs.ucf.edu/~skhan/Teaching/CDA3103_Summer2014/index.html The assignments and the other announcements will be posted on the course web site Classroom: HPA1-0116 Class Hours: Monday, Wednesday 12:00 PM - 1:50PM Office Hours: Monday, Wednesday 2:30PM - 4:00PM (in HEC-315) Pre-requisites: Some familiarity with computer science Credit Hours: 3 (3, 1) Textbook: Computer Organization and Design, Fifth Edition: The Hardware/Software Interface
Author(s) : Patterson & Hennessy (Optional)
Computer Architecture (From Microprocessor To Supercomputers)
Author(s) : Behrooz Parhami Acknowledgements: Thanks to Dr. Dan Garcia for his awesome slides on Computer Organization and Design. Course Goals: 1. Introduce fundamentals of the organization and design of computers from both the computer programmer's perspective and computer ''architect's'' perspective. 2. Cover the five basic components of a computer (input, output, memory, datapath, and control), functions of each component, and how components interact with each other and with the software systems they enable. 3. Learn Assembly Language through programming projects. 4. Explain memory hierarchy, cache, and addressing schemes. 5. Introduce hardware design of processor&rsquo;s control and datapath, including pipelining concepts. Grading: Homeworks (HW) : 25%, Programming Projects (PR) : 10%
Midterm-I: 20%, Midterm-II: 15%, MidtermFinal: 30%. Grading formula: HW = (HW1 + HW2 + HW3 + ...+ HWn) / n Pr = (Pr1 + Pr2 + Pr3 + ...+ Prn) / n Overall = 0.25 * HW + 0.10 * PR + 0.2 * Midterm1 + 0.15 * Midterm2 + 0.30 * Final HW2, PR2 etc are exactly the number you got, so if you got 112, that is what you put in.
Standard 90/80/70/60 scale will be used for final grades (curved if necessary).
Makeup Exam Police No Makeup exam or quiz will be given except for University pre-approved functions or activities. Student must provide advance written notification. Sample exams Exams given in Fall 2013
%[sample] Midterm 1
[sample] Midterm 2
[sample] Final
Note: the material covered in different exams depends due to different calendar positions of the exam and other factors. Furthermore, while the exams are representative of the style of the problems, you should not expect that the new exams are just variations with different data. Integrity: All the quizzes, homeworks, and exams are individual work.
The division, college, and University are committed to honesty and integrity in all academic matters. We do not tolerate academic misconduct by students in any form, including cheating, plagiarism and commercial use of academic materials. Please consult the Golden Rule Handbook for the procedures which will be applied. Syllabus (Tentative) Date Topics [Lecture Notes &amp; Readings] Homeworks May 12 Combinational Digital Circuits - I [Part 1] [Part 2] May 14 Combinational Digital Circuits - II [Multiplexers] [Decoders] [Controlling Gates] Homework 1 [Due 5/21] May 19 Digital Artihmetic [Number Systems] [Adders &amp; Subtractors] [ALU] [Multipliers] May 21 Digital Circuits with Memory - I [Flip-Flops] [Memory Design] Homework 2 [Due 5/28] May 26 Memorial Day [Official Holiday] No Class May 28 Midterm Exam I June 02 MIPS ISA Instruction Format [Assembly-Language] [MIPS-ISA] Reading [2.1, 2.2, 2.3, 2.5, 2.6] Project 1 [Due 6/15] June 04 MIPS ISA (Conditional Statements, Loops) [MIPS-ISA II] Reading [2.7, 2.10] Homework 3 [Due 6/11] June 09 MIPS ISA (Stacks, Functions) [Procedures and Stacks] Reading [2.8, 2.13, 2.14] June 11 Program Translation and CPU Performance [Program Translation] Reading [2.12, 2.20], [Performance] Reading [1.6, 1.7] Project 2 [Due 6/30] Homework 4 [Due 6/18] June 16 Number Representation, Floating Point Numbers, Multipliers and Dividers [Number Representation] [Floating Point Numbers] [Multipliers and Dividers] Reading [3.1 - 3.5] June 18 Logic Design, Flip Flops [Logic Design] [Flip-Flops] Reading [Appendix B.8, B.10, B.11] June 23 Midt****erm Exam II June 25 Memory Hierarchy (Main memory concepts) [Main memory concepts and Cache] [DirectMap Cache Example] Reading [5.1, 5.2, 5.3][Appendix B.9] June 30 Cache Performance and Set Associative Cache [Cache Performance and Set Associative Cache] [Summary Flowchart] Reading [5.3, 5.4, 5.5] July 02 Virtual Memory and Paging [Virtual Memory] Reading [5.7, 5.8] Homework 5 [Due 7/20] July 07 Revision Class [DirectMap Cache and Set-associative Cache] [Numericals] July 09 Single-Cycle Data Path [SingleCycle DataPath] Reading [4.1, 4.2, 4.3] July 14 CPU Control [CPU Control] Reading [4.4] July 16 Pipelining concepts, datapath and hazards [Pipelining Concepts] Reading [4.5, 4.6, 4.7] July 21 Pipelined Datapath &amp; Control [Pipelining Concepts and Parallelism] Reading [4.8, 4.10, 6.1, 6.2, 6.3, 6.5] Homework 6 [Due 7/26] July 23 Revision Class July 28 Final Exam Prep Q/A Session July 30 Final Exam (Comprehensive) Time: 12:00pm - 3:00pm ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Markdown Test</title>
    <url>/post/markdown-test/</url>
    <categories><category>测试</category>
    </categories>
    <tags>
      <tag>Markdown</tag>
    </tags>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[仅以此篇文章来测试下在 NexT 主题中在通过 Hugo 引擎来建站时，是否支持 Markdown 文件内容中所写的各种语法，并展示下实际的效果。
标题样式 让我们从所有可能的标题开始，在 HTML 中 &lt;h1&gt;-&lt;h6&gt;元素分别表示六个不同级别的标题样式，其中 &lt;h1&gt; 为最大标题，&lt;h6&gt;为最小标题，效果如下：
标题 1 标题 2 标题 3 标题 4 标题 5 标题 6 段落格式 根据 W3C 定义的 HTML5 规范 ，HTML 文档由元素和文本组成。每个元素的组成都由一个 开始标记 表示，例如： &lt;body&gt; ，和 结束标记 表示，例如： &lt;/body&gt; 。（某些开始标记和结束标记在某些情况下可以省略，并由其他标记暗示。） 元素可以具有属性，这些属性控制元素的工作方式。例如：超链接是使用 a 元素及其 href 属性形成的。
Markdown 语法 ![图像说明](图像地址) HTML IMG 标签 &lt;img src=&#34;图像地址&#34; width=&#34;宽度&#34; height=&#34;高度&#34; /&gt; SVG 格式 &lt;svg&gt;xxxxxx&lt;/svg&gt; 列表类型 有序列表 第一个元素 第二个元素 第三个元素 无序列表 列表元素 另一个元素 和其它元素 嵌套列表 借助 HTML 的 ul 元素来实现。
第一项 第二项 第二项第一个子项目 第二项第二个子项目 第二项第二分项第一分项 第二项第二分项第二分项 第二项第二分项第三分项 第二项第三个子项目 第二项第三分项第一分项 第二项第三分项第二分项 第二项第三分项第三分项 第三项 自定义列表 通过 HTML 的 dl 元素还支持自定义列表（表格列表）。
Hugo 目录结构 assets config.toml content data theme static Hugo 模板 基础模板 列表模板 单页模板 块引用 blockquote 元素表示从另一个源引用的内容，可以选择引用必须在 footer 或 cite 元素中，也可以选择使用注释和缩写等行内更改。
引用文本 这一行也是同样的引用 同样你也在 blockquote 中使用 Markdown 语法书写
带有引文的 Blockquote 元素效果。
我的目标不是赚大钱,是为了制造好的电脑。当我意识到我可以永远当工程师时，我才创办了这家公司。
— 史蒂夫·沃兹尼亚克 根据 Mozilla 的网站记录，Firefox 1.0 于 2004 年发布，并取得了巨大成功。
表格 表格并不算是 Markdown 的核心要素，但 Hugo 同样支持它。
ID 创建者 模型 年份 1 Honda Accord 2009 2 Toyota Camry 2012 3 Hyundai Elantra 2010 可以使用 : （英文格式冒号）来对表格内容进行对齐。
表格 可以是 很酷 左对齐 居中 右对齐 左对齐 居中 右对齐 左对齐 居中 右对齐 同样也可以在表格中使用 Markdown 语法。
表格 中 使用 Markdown 语法 斜体 粗体 中划线 代码块 Code &lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; &lt;html lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt; &lt;head&gt; &lt;meta charset=&#34;UTF-8&#34;&gt; &lt;title&gt;Example HTML5 Document&lt;/title&gt; &lt;/head&gt; &lt;body&gt; &lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/body&gt; &lt;/html&gt; &lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; &lt;html lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt; &lt;head&gt; &lt;meta charset=&#34;UTF-8&#34;&gt; &lt;title&gt;Example HTML5 Document&lt;/title&gt; &lt;/head&gt; &lt;body&gt; &lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/body&gt; &lt;/html&gt; 其它元素： abbr、sub、sup、kbd等等 GIF 是位图图像格式。
H2O
C6H12O6
Xn + Yn = Zn
按X获胜。或按CTRL+ALT+F显示 FPS 计数器。
比特作为信息论中的信息单位，也被称为 shannon ，以信息论领域的创始人 Claude shannon 的名字命名。
参考：
来自 Mainroad 主题的 Basic Elements 内容 ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>关于我</title>
    <url>/about.html</url>
    <categories>
    </categories>
    <tags>
    </tags>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[关于我 关于本站 这是一个关于我个人的Wiki，记录与分享日常学习中的一切思考与发现。
与我联系 Email: yeweifengde@gmail.com || wyeak@connect.ust.hk 评论区功能测试中，欢迎给我留言 同时有关我个人学习与研究项目的进展今后也会在我的 Github Page 上进行更新，期待与大家的共同进步。
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>课程信息</title>
    <url>/course.html</url>
    <categories>
    </categories>
    <tags>
    </tags>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ CDA3103 - Computer Logic and Organization ]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>工具小站</title>
    <url>/flinks.html</url>
    <categories>
    </categories>
    <tags>
    </tags>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[ 如有想要分享的小站，欢迎在下方评论区留下您的站点信息 (名称 + 链接)：
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</search>